This is basically creating Sim City for
me.
Oh, wow. That's a lot of thinking.
That is a lot of thinking, but it's way
more thinking than I've put into this.
Please. And always say please because we
don't know where this is going in future
and we need to be kind to our overlords.
Now I have to understand the game that
I've just designed.
I added four roads which the UI sucks by
the way on this. It's gone up to 100%
happiness because I've added roads.
You're listening to the AI Native Dev
brought to you by Tessa.
Hello and welcome to this episode of the
AI Native Dev. This is going to be a
really fun hands-on episode. If you're
listening via the just audio only
podcast during this episode, we will be
narrating what we're doing so you will
be able to get a feel of what's working,
what's not as we play through a number
of tools. The best probably way of
watching this is via the YouTube. Make
sure you go to ainativedev.io
to view those videos. But like I say,
you can get some enjoyment I'm sure out
of both now. This is going to be a
couple of episodes actually where we
play with a number of tools. Some very
prototype-like tools. And by that I mean
AI dev tools that create that vibe
coding applications very quickly. Tools
like bolts.new, tools base 44. Those
types of tools allow you to effectively
write even just a couple of sentences
and get a whole app created as a result
as you'll see. During this exercise,
we're going to have Macy provide us with
a challenge and we're going to start off
in this episode with us trying that vibe
coding a very quick generation of those
tools. In this episode, we're going to
be using base 44 and bolts.new. In the
next episode, we're going to do this as
two parts. In the next episode, which
will be out next week, what you're going
to be seeing is us taking those
applications that are created and using
tools that are a little bit more
surgical in their approach to AI code
generation. And we're going to use both
Windsurf and Cursor to add features to
the existing creations from those two
tools. So, during this episode, like I
say, it's going to be myself and Joe
Holdcroft, both Teslas, who are going to
be doing that creating and narrating
that to you. Enjoy the episode. I'll
hand over to myself. Simon, it's over to
you.
Hello and welcome to another episode of
the AI Native Dev. My name is Simon
Maple and we are going to be doing a fun
vibe coding game today. So, joining
myself today is Joe Holdcroft. Welcome,
Joe. How are you?
I'm good.
Happy to be here. First time on the
First time on the podcast. What do you
do at Tesla, Joe?
I'm an engineering manager at Tesla, so
writing code and helping make things
happen.
You sound extremely smart. Very smart.
I'm glad
And joining us a little bit later will
also be Macy Baigs, Macy Baker, who is
going to be giving us a vibe coding
challenge. So, this is we call also call
this a vibe coding relay, right? Neither
of us has seen this challenge before.
We're both going to be using completely
separate tools. I'm going to be using
Base 44 and Cursor. Joe, you're going to
be using
Bolt and Windsurf.
Bolt and Windsurf. Amazing. And Macy's
going to provide us with a challenge
that neither of us has seen. We're going
to have 10-ish minutes perhaps to do
some live vibe coding. That needs a
name. What is that?
Live coding.
Yeah.
Live workshopping.
Live coding. And yeah, then we're going
to swap code bases. We're going to have
an additional feature to code. And we're
probably going to go less from a
prototypy style tool, which is the kind
of Bolt and Base 44 tools, and more into
one of those hands-on, a little bit
closer to the code with Cursor and
Windsurf.
Cool. So, let's see how this goes. Joe,
I'm going to click my fingers and you're
going to turn into Macy by the power of
editing. Are you ready?
I'm ready.
Ready? Three,
two, one. Wow, Macy, you appeared.
Hey.
That was so not impressive for people
only on the audio only, but
I know, yeah.
Joining us is Macy Baker.
Now, Macy, this is less stressful for
you because you're passing over the
challenge versus coding it. Welcome
back. This is your third time on the
podcast.
As I keep saying, I do work here, so.
Yeah, yeah. And if we had a third time
like gift,
now would be the time I'd be passing
that over to you.
This is my gift because I just get to
watch you two struggle with this. No,
it's not going to be hard. It's going to
be fun. I'm excited. I'm excited.
to be hard for us to struggle.
Yeah. Let's see.
So, tell us a little bit about this
challenge then, Macy, or are you going
to pass that over?
Yeah, so this is a surprise. This is a
request that I have. It's not a full fat
prompt. I've left it intentionally a
little bit vague because I'm really
curious
how you both interpret it. So, I'm
excited to see see what you do.
Awesome.
So, I'm going to give this to you. You
have a few minutes to think if you need
that time. I have some note paper for
you. Otherwise, 10-ish minutes to get
going.
Okay. Awesome.
Thank you. So, let me open this up
and take a look at our
challenge within.
Okay, I was expecting this to actually
be a lot a lot bigger in terms of how
much information there is. Build a tiny
town simulator. You have 10 minutes.
Yes, so build a tiny town simulator. My
mind goes to Do you remember that game
Sim City?
Yeah, huge fan.
Huge fan. I used to love that. I'm
thinking Okay, so there's going to be a
number of pieces here. There's going to
be the simulator engine itself. There's
also going to be the UI, which is going
to need to display that, and something
I've only got 10 minutes, so something
to actually keep a time check as well,
so that every day or every hour of every
day something happens, almost like the
kind of like the life gen style thing
where it recognizes how many people if
it's too busy. So, something to display,
some kind of time check, I would say.
We're going to I'll probably stick with
the SimCity where we have a number of
different things. So, we have a
residential, we'll have a work industry.
What was the third thing? Can you
remember what the third thing was? There
was three things.
It's quite a lot going on in SimCity to
be honest.
or something like that.
It's like municipalities,
hospital, transport.
But, this is totally up to you.
I'm going to start small. We've only got
10 minutes, so I'm going to start small.
I think that's wise.
Let me share my screen. And I'm going to
I'm going to go over to base 64.
Base 44, is it?
Base What did I say? Base 64? Base 64.
Oh, dear.
Old school.
Goes to show my security background
there.
What made you want to try this? Where
did you hear about it?
I've used a lot of Bolt
in the past. I've heard base 44
described as Bolt, but better. So, I'm
actually really keen to have a play with
this. For the record, I've not touched
this before, but when I look at the
screen, it To be honest, it looks like a
it looks like a non-dark mode of Bolt,
which I'm absolutely happy with. I am a
big dark mode fan, but we'll see how
this goes. So, yeah, I just essentially
have a box that I'm going to say build a
tiny
town simulator. Let's do that and see
what happens. Cuz that'll be funny if it
just builds me SimCity. And this is the
wonderful thing about these kind of
prototype style apps, that it knows,
obviously, about a SimCity and these
other tiny these other town simulators.
So, it could potentially create a lot of
this for me without me even needing to
ask.
Yeah, I think this feels like the path
of least resistance to me also. It's
just see what it has in mind and kind of
play along with that. Like these
prototyping tools
they're iterating on a a very specific
vision can be a bit tough.
Yeah, and I think the more detailed the
prompt, the more detailed the challenge,
probably the harder it is for a tool
like a base 44 or a bolt to then be able
to create that for me. Let's see what
it's doing. It's created a building
entity, a town entity, a building
catalog component, and a town grid
component. Okay, so this feels a little
bit UI based. Wow, you see this is it's
creating so much you know I haven't
asked here. It's creating now town
stats.
Town stats. Okay, interesting.
Which I expect a new town dialogue. This
is basically creating SimCity for me.
Yeah, I'm interested in I can't really
remember what role did people have in
SimCity. You don't necessarily work with
specific people. It's more like crowds
as an entity.
I think it was
using things.
The Sims allowed you to have an
individual person where you can click on
them and get information about them.
Much more of a Sims girl.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Okay, I never really played that too
much, but the SimCity it much more kind
of said you've got this many people in
your city and cared about the balance
between population versus like you say
the police or the fire stations and
things like that.
Now, I wonder what the relationships are
between these entities and like how it
decided on this order. Seems to me that
it's going from the bottom up. So now it
says it's editing simulator page and I'm
wondering if that means
it's getting towards the end.
Yeah. It's done everything from building
records to town records and things like
that.
Okay, so it says, is it pretty much
done? Created a tiny simulator, tiny
town simulator where you can build and
manage various buildings, earn income,
and grow population over time. Some
errors were detected. It's going to try
and fix them automatically. Let's have a
look. There's no upgrade icon in Lucid
React library, so it's chosen JavaScript
as I would expect. A lot of these use
that kind of like React-based thing.
Claude Claude code did that first. Well,
not not Claude Claude artifacts did that
first. The way I created that that React
component bolts very similar.
Um
Yeah, we're seeing a lot of similar
behaviors even in the initial
interaction. This is interesting, so
it's responded to itself.
Yeah.
You're right. I'll replace the
non-existent upgrade icon. That's funny.
Okay, so it said it's it's fixed it.
I've not used this before, so where is
it?
So, for those just listening, it said
there's an error, I'll fix it, and then
it and then nothing happened.
I clicked off and I clicked back on and
now look. Oh, wow, this is it.
Oh, wow, here we go.
This is insane. Okay, so it's given me a
population of five, a happiness, a
treasury, so I've got a budget. Didn't
even think about that. An income. Okay,
so yeah, this makes sense in the sense
of me being able to to be able to charge
people for rent or whatever it is, have
an income. I can create a new town. I
can save. I have a building catalog with
residential, commercial, industrial,
special, park, hospital, school. Oh,
wow, look, this is it.
Oh, wow, cute. It's just gone for like a
a grid layout.
better.
Oh, and it's very responsive. Love that.
What if I click on workspace? So, this
is my Okay, this is a Oh, no. Is it So,
this is data. So, these are my These are
the tables and things that it's added.
So, I've got a building table and a town
table in my data.
I've got a bunch of code. So, this has
got to This is the Yeah, here's my code.
So, this is not It's funny how we didn't
realize where the difference was, where
the line was between the editor and the
actual app then, but this is the This is
more of the editor, so I can see my
code. I can see my components. I've got
a building catalog, a town grid, town
stats, and new town dialog for as in
components for my page. I have two
entities, one is a building, one is a
town. So, let's go back to editor. So,
what I would want to do, I think I feel
like interestingly this is too complex
for what I want. So, what I want is I'm
going to say, "Make the following
following changes to this app. I want I
want there to be a timer which ends the
day automatically
after 1 minute." Okay, let's make these
things that I want to change. The second
thing I want to change, let's see.
I don't want the new town option to be
available or to be visible. Let's make
this nice and simple. I want auto save
to happen on changes, please. And always
say please because I don't know where
this is going in future and we need to
be kind to our overlords. Please remove
the save button. I can add houses, add
apartment buildings. So, what I don't
want. Let's keep residential. Let's
actually play with it a little bit.
Let's add a house.
Look at that, I can add that there. Then
it reloads the town. I can add an
apartment building.
your income changed when you did that.
Yeah, and my treasury went down.
happiness
Happiness has gone up. Add a luxury
condo. I want to add roads. And let's
send that as an example. So, do you know
what's super interesting? This is This
has allowed me basically, if you look at
the request that you had, build a tiny
town simulator. You have 10 minutes. I
needed 2 minutes to do that and that's
insane. That's ridiculous.
Yeah, that was ridiculous.
And and I think it builds so so much in
for me. The task of building a tiny town
simulator is just with this type of
prototyping software is just way too
easy. I think the thing that was
interesting was when I requested it,
because the ask was vague,
my ask to Base 44 here could be vague,
and what it gave me wasn't actually what
was in my mind. But there's pros and
cons of that, right? The pro of that is
I can create this super quickly, and
actually it'll create me things that I
hadn't even thought about.
Yeah.
The problem with that is though, I just
wanted something very simple. I had in
my mind a SimCity, which this is a
little bit like, but also not quite
like.
Yeah, I'm curious like how much this
deviates from what you had in your mind.
Yeah. Changing things is very easy
though. I don't know what the next step
is, what the next feature request is
going to be, but I feel I could probably
do that quite easy, probably more easy
in this than I would in Cursor, which
I've used a fair bit as well. But yeah,
we'll see how this goes. So I can add
roads now as well.
I'm curious about the This must just be
like a known dynamic because each of
these objects has a defined amount of
happiness and cost and whatever. Is
anything negative happiness? Because
your happiness is 100%.
I added four roads, which the UI sucks
by the way on this, and it's added me
It's gone It's gone up to 100% happiness
because I've added roads.
Everyone is freaking out about the
roads.
As long as I Everyone is way too happy.
I want there to be a more realistic
balance on happiness. Oh, did you see
that? It's switched to day two now. Oh,
look.
Oh, your timer works.
top right. So it's added a timer top
right. It's telling me what day it is.
I've got daily income, which now means
my treasury increases. Yes, I've gone
from 400 now to 427 because my daily
income's gone up to 27. Actually, I just
realized, where does my daily income
even come from? Oh, it comes from
Coming from the buildings.
Yeah, look, everything adds happiness,
but nothing removes happiness. Oh, no.
Roads.
Oh, Oh, look at that.
Roads cost you money.
My roads cost me money every day. So,
obviously for wear and tear.
Small factories reduce happiness. A
power plant reduces 10 happiness.
Wow. Why don't the people like power?
Yeah. I was going to put I was going to
put a power plant by every house, but
that doesn't seem to be a thing now. So,
when there's be more realistic balance
on happy happiness. And there we go.
We're on day three now. And I got 454.
And I also want to say
roads suck. The images need to make the
square look like a road. And if
adjoining squares are both roads,
they should join. My son's just started
playing a ton of Jurassic World. And
this is what I'm thinking I want to see
now.
Speaking of timers, by the way.
How am I doing?
Three minutes.
Three minutes. This is Do you know
what's weird is It's amazing I've only
been 7 minutes and I've already got way
more than what I thought I I was going
to get in this this app.
Yeah. So, now it becomes Keep in mind,
the next phase is going to be Joe's
going to get the same prompt.
Yeah.
And then you're going to have to edit
Joe's work. And he's going to have to
edit this.
Oh, this is interesting.
So, I wonder if you want to do anything
with that in mind.
Absolutely.
I'm going to change the code to make it
more complex. I want I'm just going to
say I'll escape the code. Would that be
really mean to Joe?
Oh, you're free to do that.
what's he going to do to me?
That is the question.
You see, I'm trying to make this
simpler. I'm I'm giving Joe an easier an
easier next round, aren't I? The
bottleneck for me now isn't the coding.
It's actually You're the bottleneck,
Macy. I need more information now as to
as to to to the spec in order for this
to actually go further. So, what's it
doing now? It's editing the building
catalog component for some reason. Oh,
for happiness.
It's editing the town grid component.
So, that will presumably allow the roads
to actually look like roads and
adjoining squares to uh to look like
roads as well.
I do really like the What do you call
it? Like the little
circle, the loading indicator. Seems
silly, but like
On the
so many of these prototypes Yeah, on the
actual components. But so many of these
prototyping tools, they're just you
shoot into the ether and
Yeah.
who knows what's going on.
And if I was to actually to spend a
minute while this is doing this to
compare this with Bolt, which I've used
a lot. This is loads It feels loads
slower than Bolt in terms of I put in a
prompt, it takes a lot longer for me to
actually get something back. But what I
have got back, it feels way more
complete. But if I was to ask Bolt for
the same thing, I have this feeling that
it would be nowhere near as capable as
what has been shown already.
Interesting. I have to say, I'm a big
fan of the workspace page once I
understood what exactly it was. So this
is like all of the controls for this app
in one place, including the data stores
and everything, which
Yeah.
is really nice. And there's even a place
there for custom domains if you want to
just go ahead and publish this, which is
very cool.
And this is one of the other things I
think is going to be interesting with
when we look at the next set of tools,
when we look at Cursor and Wind Surf. I
haven't I Since I clicked on workspace,
which is really to understand what
workspace was, oh my god, that road
looks awful. For those who For those who
are watching, you'll know what I mean.
For those just listening to the audio
only, it's just basically colored these
The square is just now a color, a solid
color. So that just looks ridiculous.
a giant obelisk in the city.
Yeah, and I think the roads What do
roads do? Roads are there zero
happiness. Oh yeah, I also asked it to
be more grumpy, didn't I? Apartment
buildings are Oh look, apartment
buildings are minus two happiness.
Oh.
How rude.
That's rude.
Yeah, but a small house is plus two
happiness.
Oh, what they really want is a shopping
mall.
Oh, how did you know that? Oh, I see.
Yeah, yeah.
Plus five.
Uh one thing I would change is I would
say "Give me advice on Give me as a user
of the app advice on what I need to do
next."
Interesting. What are you hoping it'll
say?
it to say "Actually, we didn't We
haven't actually got much here on
needs." Like if there was a ton of
houses, I would obviously need more
commercial stuff, more industrial stuff,
very similar to SimCity. But so I would
want it to kind of prompt me to say
"Actually, yeah, you've got too many
houses. You need more industry." or
something like that.
Like these things also should be
progressively changing, I feel. The
population, the happiness, etc. Like
it's very fixed
Yeah.
right now to these objects. Kind of
interesting.
One thing I did notice is that states
remained if my republished then. So I
went from day six to day seven.
Yeah.
Uh oh, interesting.
Have you noticed since I actually made
those changes? So it's made that change
now. Is there advice?
Same with the Same with the objects.
Like the houses that you put, these
don't get reset.
Yeah.
The data is static, which is really
cool.
Yeah, yeah. Uh okay, I've got tips now,
which is absolutely useless.
Okay, so it's interpreted your question
as I'm going to add tips. See, that has
And this is what I've spoken to you
about before, the overeagerness to just
code.
Yeah.
Like sometimes that's not what you want.
what I want. It should have asked me
questions.
It totally it should have asked you
questions. And what would you do if you
wanted to go back a version, for
example? It has got a little revert this
Oh, yeah.
button on your chat, which is
interesting.
That is interesting. So let's see if I
revert. Oh, I didn't even read that. I
just clicked something. What's it Okay.
So tips, that was quick. It just It
reverted back, but
Okay, so it's obviously got some kind of
versioning.
It doesn't feel like there's
huge version control in here, but maybe
single user revert stuff looks more like
a state style thing.
One interesting thing there is I've
never since clicking workspace I've
never clicked back. All I've really been
doing is
Yeah.
talking to it and looking. So, it's very
vibe coding.
Very much that.
I think I'm done there. I think I think
that's my 10 minutes. I want to pass
that back over to to Joe to see what to
see what happens with Joe.
Can I ask before we move on, what did
you think of base 44?
In terms of rapid acceleration from idea
1 2 3 4 5 words that I posted in build a
tiny town simulator to what seems like a
fully working fully working reasonable
click tested app that does certain
things that I expected it to do.
Yeah.
Uh really amazing. It would take me well
over a week to do something like that
with my very limited front end skills.
Joe is much much more of a front end
developer, so he's probably going to
look at this and feel like it's
absolutely bastardizing his his
question. But, for me, yeah, this is
amazing. I'm not looking at the code, so
I don't know anything about the quality,
the testing, the testing of the app.
Sure. Sure.
But, but yeah, for me this is magic that
this has happened.
Okay. Great.
Let's move to Joe. Let's click our
fingers and then Joe will appear.
All right, Joe.
All right. Thanks very much.
That's for you.
Lovely envelope. Okay. Build a tiny town
simulator.
You have 10 minutes. That is pretty
open-ended.
Thoughts? What comes to mind?
Tiny town. I'm imagining like a sort of
dumbed-down version of SimCity.
It's pretty complicated.
A game, but
It is.
probably not all of those aspects. Or
those iOS games that you get advertised
on if you're on the cheap Duolingo plan,
which I know for a fact that you're not.
But, they're all build a farm and farm
carrots and things like that.
Like those like the farming ones where
it's more modular.
Yeah, something like that. Interested in
this like SimCity route. Like you're
you're not a player necessarily, you're
like a a
designing a town and building houses and
resources and things like that.
Like what are the objects? What are the
main things that must
be in the town?
Yeah, what makes up a town? So, you've
got the residences, houses, apartments,
things like that. I feel like you need
some public amenities. Hospital is
always good
to have.
Nice.
A fire station and police. What happens
in this town? Maybe they can
first things on the list are hospital
and fire station.
I feel like
to be some jeopardy here. Not a lot of
good stuff. Um but yeah, maybe there's
like a events that come up. They could
be like positive events or bad events. I
haven't used Bolt before. I don't know
how good it's going to be at making a
game. This might be incredibly
ambitious.
Let's see.
I'm worried about making it a little bit
too overcomplicated. So, maybe I should
not add too many types of event or too
many types of thing.
Yeah, I think that's probably a good
idea.
This is also, for those listening, Joe's
first time using Bolt, which is very
exciting.
My first time using Bolt. Very excited.
I'm interested to just see like where I
get to. So, I'm I'd like to find out
quickly whether I'm like barking up the
wrong tree and this is just it's not
going to get anywhere close to what I'm
trying to do. So, I think I'm going to
move to a prompt and see what I can come
up with. So, build a mini game that
simulates a tiny town. The player is
tasked with designing their town which
comprises of the following features.
Residences,
hospitals,
Hospitals.
fire station, police station. And let's
say let's something more positive, maybe
like a community center or like a an
events an event space. Let's say
community center.
Yeah, you need a place where people can
get hurt so they can go to the hospital.
That is true.
Yeah, I'm like when I think of a game
like
It's not really a game, is it, yet? It's
more
Yeah. I guess it's Maybe I'm going to
Yeah.
It's like a It's more of a simulator
than a game. I guess you could say the
same of like SimCity. Like people call
it a game, but it you can't really win
this or lose. It's just
But then can you die?
I don't know. Cuz does your town
Well, but in The Sims you don't die.
You're like a character dies.
Well, speak for yourself.
Very painful for some of us.
Yeah, okay. Fair.
So, build a mini town
simulator. At random intervals,
events will take place
to test the setup of the town and its
efficiency. Is that what we care about?
Okay, interesting. What are these like
black swan events? What kind of events
are they?
Okay, events. Examples of events that
you can expand. It's not an exhaustive
list. Maybe there's some sort of like
community event like something in the
community center happens. So, like let's
say let's just say a music event in the
community center. A fire
takes place
somewhere. Oh, what about new people
move into the town? They need a
residence.
Oh, wow. Housing crisis.
Yeah. I'm already thinking that the
scope of this is too large and I have no
idea what's going to happen when I press
this button. I haven't used Bolt before,
so I don't know whether this is woefully
underspecified or not.
Let's see.
Well, let's find out. I'm seeing some
reasoning. What is it thinking?
Oh, wow. That's a lot of thinking.
That is a lot of thinking. It's way more
thinking than I've put into this.
It's very IDE.
Yeah. Yeah, so I'm dropped into a sort
of IDE environment. I can see that it's
building what looks like a React
application.
Yeah.
As far as I can tell, it's starting to
build some components now and some state
management. So, if I was building this
in React for myself,
I I would be very angry at myself for
giving myself a task like this.
I don't want to be building a
complicated SimCity style game in React.
But that's fine. I have another one to
do that for Oh, I see it's it's inferred
some sort of statistics about the town.
There's a treasury we have money in the
town.
Oh, that's cool cuz we didn't really say
how we wanted it to be in.
Yeah.
Scored or even timekeeping or anything.
I assume when there's fires the
happiness level is low.
That would be
like that would be important to test.
Are there any tests? There's not going
to be any tests I don't think.
It is not generating test currently, but
that's fine. It would only make Simon's
life easier when we get to the
iteration.
Yeah, that's the thing.
So this is seems to be the state man Oh,
no, this is where random events.
So
where does the event take place? Need to
find a building, pick a random set Okay,
so you can have parties outside of
buildings. That's cool.
Or crime.
I forgot about crime.
What the health emergency? Oh my god, do
you know what? It's too soon.
Way too soon.
Health emergency is worse if the
hospital is far away. That is true.
Crime is worse if the police station is
far away. That's philosophical
point.
Yeah, interesting. Okay, so we've got
severity for events. Is there any other
properties?
Oh, looks like we have an application.
Streams preview.
Okay, cool.
Wow, okay.
So now I have to understand the game
that I've just designed. It's not a
game, a simulator.
A simulator.
So it's given me $10,000 to start with
which doesn't seem like enough to build
a town, but we'll give it a go and 70%
for the happiness safety and health.
Yeah, that's a little tight I would say.
So let's see if I can build I'm going to
put row of houses here,
row of houses here.
So it actually made it did make
everything that you asked for. It
doesn't seem like it's missing anything.
It hasn't missed anything. It wasn't
super well specified and it has added a
bunch of things as well. Like it's added
this concept of money which I realize I
think I'm getting these houses for free.
The treasure I still have $10,000.
Oh, well.
Unless that happens when I move to the
next day, I don't know. Okay, so that's
Okay, so that's a little janky. Right.
Yeah, okay. Fire station.
Let's put some more houses in.
should be well broke by now.
Let's see what happens. I love this bug
though. It'd be great if life worked
like that. Infinite infinite money. Day
two begins. Income $0. Well, that's fine
cuz I've got infinite money anyway.
Well, that's fine cuz yeah, Rosebud
hack.
And now it seems like nothing's
happened, but am I waiting or
That's a good question. I feel like the
timing of everything
It's funny. So, I'm going to advance to
the next day again. Day three begins.
Income $0. Nothing's happened still.
to get income? That's a question.
Good point. Taxes maybe? People come and
pay taxes?
when are these events going to happen?
It doesn't seem to be doing much of
anything. The sort of the design for
this grid system thing is kind of nice.
Well, look at it.
It's fine. I've maybe evolved the emojis
into some incredibly great detailed
little hand-drawn icons, but So, it
seems like nothing happens in this town.
And nobody comes into the town.
No money is
No money is spent. No events happen.
And the stats never move, which is
interesting.
Yeah, the stats never change. Nothing is
happening basically. So, I guess I'm
going to go into the prompt and tell the
other land that it has not delivered on
its promise. So, this is where I find
out how bold is the iteration.
Yeah, and bug fixing.
It doesn't seem to do anything as I move
through the days. Nobody comes to the
town. Population stays at zero.
And no events happen. Also,
I seem to be able
to spend infinite amounts of money.
Prefer it didn't fix that, but it would
be good if it did.
Let's see. Main problem are in the event
system timing and the game logic for
population growth and money management
that would make sense.
diagnosed that really quickly.
But it has it diagnosed it cuz it just
said the main problem is that the stuff
doesn't work that you have said doesn't
work. It's not like the root cause is
this particular bug. So it's rewriting
at least it has the appear- Oh yes, it's
rewriting some of the files but not all
of them.
Okay.
So that's cool. Event system, let's see
if any of this is reduced to 10 seconds
for more frequent events. That seems to
indicate that I should leave it. Is this
a real-time simulator? This is not
it says you you have to press to
advance.
Mhm. So maybe in the day it's Surely I
don't have to wait 24 hours before I
click the button.
Okay, let's see.
Okay, there's still this bug and I still
seem to have infinite money. Two
hospitals next to each other for some
reason.
There's no one in the There's no one
here but they're but who but the
sentiment of happiness has dropped
significantly.
they so unhappy?
Nobody is very unhappy. Day three Aha,
this is new. Day three begins. Income
zero, maintenance minus zero, population
zero. So it still doesn't seem to be
doing anything.
People aren't moving here because the
happiness is 30%.
And there's nobody even there.
What if I just put loads of community
centers everywhere? Will that bring joy?
No.
Seems like it will change the statistics
once and then nothing happens. Maybe
I've given it too complicated of a task
but let's see. It seems that nothing
happens still. The main issue seems to
be that population never grows so the
other statistics get stuck. Wow, fire
caused significant damage.
If fire station distance equals
infinity.
I was supposed to you don't have a fire
station.
It's infinitely far away, yeah.
Infinitely far away.
But this seems like it has some nice
like feedback for the user and some
that's pretty basic, but ah nobody went
to the music menu.
Yeah, the logic for these events is
really quite cool.
It seems sound. I get my
intuition is that there's probably just
a small bug somewhere that's making
nothing work, which has
the appearance of less stuff working.
Okay, I've already spent all of my
money.
left. So, you only have a couple minutes
left.
Oh gosh. Okay.
mind that Simon is going to take over
this code base and expand it.
Interesting.
Is there anything you want to change?
In anticipation of that.
I could trip him up.
Yeah.
I could obfuscate the code or make it
more difficult to work with, which feels
a little unfair because it already
doesn't work.
Like I I cannot get anyone to move into
this town no matter what.
just pretend that you did that on
purpose. There you
Job done.
This is my town. It's like an an
abandoned town from
It's a ghost town.
It's a ghost town. It's been like
designed and no one's moved in. It's
immediately become a ghost town.
Brutal.
So, how long have I got? I want to give
one more go at trying to get it to
actually work and I'm interested to
obfuscate the code a little bit make
Simon's life a little tricky.
Two minutes.
Two minutes. Okay, let's do
Okay.
Please fix the population growth. A
random
but sensible number of new town folk
Town folk?
will arrive every day.
This can also be zero.
I like that. I feel honestly I have a
huge amount of trust in LLMs for
defining what sensible means.
I can't tell if you're being sarcastic
there or not. No, okay.
It wasn't always the case, but now I'm
like, I can just say don't make it
insane and it has some idea of what that
is.
Okay, I think I'm in a stuck state. This
message didn't complete its response and
it's spinning.
So, it's nice having, yeah.
That's how you would go back is just by
clicking undo. Not that you should do
that.
Oh, I see. You're going through the
version. Undo each individual change
that you made. Interesting, yeah.
Oh, it's kind of a nightmare though to
do one thing at a time.
But I wonder if you can, cuz it I see
that undo's disabled on the previous
ones. But
Oh, interesting. Maybe it's only got
like previous and current
Mhm.
as versions. Interesting. Okay, so the
game reducer is getting a lot of action.
I feel like this has been edited quite a
few times.
Yeah. This appears to be where all the
state management stuff is happening,
which makes sense cuz that's clearly
where the bugs are.
It's also just quite
long. And I'm always I'm so curious how
they do like context management for
these things.
I'm not getting any population
growth. And so at this point, I guess I
probably need to jump into the code,
which I really don't want to do,
especially if I'm going to obfuscate it.
It's so readable.
Yeah.
It seems like totally defensible code,
but there is a lot of it. And I wonder
how much of it is being actually used.
If these are all different state
management changes that can happen, it
doesn't appear that any of these are
someone new comes to town, unless that's
an event. What is the town of Okay, so
it's a shame I can't jump around in this
IDE.
Oh, yeah, you can't command click.
Yeah.
That is a bit of a shame. Although, can
you Not that you probably are motivated
to do this, but you could export it.
I could, but I'm going to make some more
changes to it. But maybe I could
just export it at this point, just
before I mess everything up and make it
really hard.
It's not a lightning fast download,
jeez.
Okay, event types. So, there's no event
for new Oh, no, there is new residents.
It's just not happening. It's just not
happening. So, the severity of new
residents is positive.
Okay.
Okay. I don't know I don't know where it
Okay, resolve event. New residents has
residency. Okay, so there's some
feedback for dealing with the residents,
the new resident, but where's the code
that actually makes Okay, trigger random
event. Try to find a building for the
event.
Oh, it's literally just highlighting it
for the map.
like narrowing down the context.
Fine.
I tried three times to get it to fix it
now. So, I don't have
super high hopes.
That's fair.
That it's going to do it again. Like,
what actually does the triggering of the
random event event system component?
Okay, so it is actually
Maybe I'm playing the game wrong. But,
not game, it's a simulator. But, it does
seem to have a
Every 10 seconds an event should be
happening.
It We have definitely looked at it for
more than 10 seconds.
Does seem that way, doesn't it?
I don't believe that's happening.
Yeah. Okay, let's try one more time.
Okay.
Events are not firing.
Maybe we should simplify it. Like, maybe
the event should happen when you advance
to the next day rather than sitting
there staring at a screen. Can we
instead make events happen when the user
advances to the next day?
Multiple events could happen on a single
new day. There should be no
set interval
firing events throughout the day. Only
when I've said the same thing two or
three times here. This is bad prompting.
Only when you advance
to the next day.
This is not a bad prompting. This is
very This is an actual professional
software engineer prompting a tool like
this.
Okay.
Like, this the LM behind this is not a
software engineer. Like, it's just not
thinking about things in the same way.
So, it's interesting.
So, it's updated the event system and
the reducer where all the state
management is, which makes sense. So,
what is the event system? Okay, this is
emergency app. So, this is interesting
because I think this is going to say
that unless there's some logic for this
elsewhere, it's going to say that new
townfolk coming to town is an emergency.
I guess if they need a house, it could
be conceived as
emergency for them.
No, it's possible it's possible that
I've made it worse because it's possible
that the game did work before when you
we were waiting.
So, I might actually undo this. And
maybe it simplified it.
Can I see like a diff?
I don't think so.
Yeah, there is no diffing, is there? And
as you say, it can only go back like one
one request, it seems.
I will revert that because I have even
less faith that it's doing anything.
If it's simplified and still didn't
work.
Sad.
I could possibly say that if we just sit
and wait here, something might happen,
but it's not clear to me. I guess what
I'd need to do now is I'd start like
attaching a debugger or putting some
console logs in there and seeing like
what's actually going on.
But you'd actually have to get in and
diagnose what's happening because
the tool itself is not really
giving you loads of help.
No. I could I suppose I could ask,
rather than say fix it, say why is it
not working. I wonder if that might
help. Why are no events firing?
My population never goes higher than
zero. So, here's the issue.
the issue. Okay.
Event system isn't properly triggering
because the dev Oh, this is interesting.
The dev server is running. That's That's
the whole point of Bolt here, right? Is
that it's showing me
it's running this code and showing me
the output of it. That's
funny that it doesn't
How funny.
Wait, so it wasn't running the server
before?
It must be because this is the output of
running the server here.
And here you go. NPM run dev. But I
guess the LLM doesn't understand that
I'm in this context of
using Bolt, essentially.
I just noticed that you burned through
quite a lot of tokens.
Oh, yeah. Interesting.
250k.
Wow.
That's like quite a lot. And
unfortunately, quite a lot in this loop
of like just
No progress.
Please fix this thing.
Yeah, I haven't
I realized the value yet. Although the
initial scaffold I'd say was pretty
impressive.
For sure.
The actual sort of getting it working,
less
It even gave you a copyright. Can you go
back to the preview?
Oh, yeah.
Copyright Tiny Town Simulator.
Congrats. Okay.
Okay, so maybe I'll just wrap this up
with use my some of my little remaining
tokens to make this a little I don't
know, should I make it more complicated
for Simon? It's already fairly fairly
obtuse in some parts. Maybe I'll do
something a little bit more
approachable.
Replace the function and variable names
with funny and somewhat difficult to
understand names
to confuse the developer
who has to work with this code base.
Which is not an instruction I'd often
give at work.
I'm curious what it'll come out with. If
it's too If it's too unfair, then maybe
we'll just use my downloaded version,
but
I'm I'm interested to see what it comes
up
Okay, so
YOLO meter.
even do that?
So, it hasn't actually updated the core
code by the looks of it. It's just
importing them as like aliasing aliasing
them to a different name. So, the chaos
outcome is called the YOLO meter, and
the town vibes is called town mood,
which if anything sounds
Tweak town mood. That's not even that
confusing.
Initial chaos, YOLO prices, money drain.
Money drain?
I I wonder if this has fixed it.
That's not confusing. I like how it
changed initial state to initial chaos.
Yeah.
Very edgy
The initial chaos is nothing. There's no
No one here. Everything's fine.
Yeah, the chaos is nothing's happening.
Okay, so this hasn't really had the
desired effect. That's fine. I think
he's probably going to struggle with it
enough.
And it looks like I've probably haven't
got enough tokens to really What I'd
like to do is put a bunch of comments
throughout the code to mislead the
developer, but perhaps that's unfair. I
probably haven't got the tokens for it.
I feel like he'll have some trouble with
it as it is, but let's see.
Fair enough. Okay, cool.
Okay, cool.
It's a good one.
Nice job.
Thank you. Okay, and that pretty much
wraps up part one of this pretty fun
experiment where we're now at the stage
where both Joe and I have created two
tiny town examples of an application
whereby Joe used Bolt.db, I used Base64,
and the next step of that challenge is
for us to take each other's creations.
I'm going to be using Cursor, and Joe's
going to be using Windsurf to add a new
feature that Macy will provide us once
again. So, look out for that next week.
Thanks for listening, and tune in to the
next episode. Bye for now.
Thanks for tuning in. Join us next time
on the AI Native Dev, brought to you by
Tessel.